David Bowers

E-mail: dnlbowers@gmail.com | Tel: +356 99940969 | GitHub: https://github.com/dnlbowers

Professional Profile:

Junior developer currently enrolled in a Full stack Software Development Diploma while actively pursuing an entry into the world of development. I have been working in tech as NOC Engineer for the past three years, which showed me I love all things code. I have always worked with people in various settings, as can be seen in my work experience in sales, customer support, and the social sector.

This high exposure to people from all walks of life has left me with a diverse mindset that is keen to learn, brings passion to the table and constantly works towards a harmonious environment

Technical Skills:

<u>Technologies</u>	<u>Version control</u>
HTML5	GIT
CSS3	
JavaScript	
Python	
C#	

Work History:

08/2018 - Present - NOC Engineer.

Greentube Malta SEE Ltd. W Business Centre, Level 4, Dun Karm Street, B'Kara, Malta. I began in Greentube as a customer service representative within the first nine months they saw my ability to learn and personal knowledge of technology. By connecting to the NOC team and sitting in my own time to learn the role I was quickly transitioned into my first role in tech. My current role as a NOC engineer includes: -

- Using monitoring tools Kibana, AppDynamics, Apica monitoring system, check MK, KPIs.
- B2B partner communication.
- Incident/Change Management.
- Creating Knowledge base articles.
- Cross department communications.
- Technical trouble shooting.

<u>09/2016 - 07/2018 - Sales Leader.</u>

MDF Trading LTD (JYSK Franchisee), Triq il-Mosta, Hal-Lija, Malta.

- Reporting directly to the manager and directors to ensure smooth operation of the shop.
- Organizing and maintaining the shop floor.
- Staff Training and induction.
- Team leadership, conflict resolution and staff retention.
- Order Processing.
- Stocktaking and Investigating stock discrepancies.
- Compiling reports.
- Managing Facebook page.
- Setting targets and following up to ensure they are met.
- Managing email correspondence.
- Cash handling and ordering.
- Inputting of Purchase orders and Surcharges.
- Issuing B2C and B2B quotes.

01/2013 - 09/2016 - Customer Services and Sales Representative.

HSBC Call Centre,Tower Road, Swatar, Malta.

- Coaching and Training members of the team.
- Creating and presenting power point presentations.
- Answering telephone and email enquiries.
- Sales
- Processing financial applications.
- Time management Meeting strict deadline and targets.
- Creating motivational incentives aimed at improving the teams KPI's.

<u>04/2011 - 09/2012 - Personal Assistant.</u>

James Rose (Independent film maker) Tree Tops, Airlie Lane, Winchester, Hampshire, SO22 4WB, United Kingdom.

04/2011 - 04/2012 - Charity Fundraiser - Hampshire Wildlife Trust.

CM Fundraising 22 Tresillian Street, Hampshire County, PL4 0QW, United Kingdom.

01/2011 - 05/2011 - Education Program Coordinator.

Thekchen Buddhist Centre, 76 Whitworth Cresent, Bitterne Park, Southampton, SO18 1GA

<u>08/2008 - 11/2010 - Contact supervisor.</u>

RSD Technology LTD, Kingsway, Fforestfach, Swansea, SA5 4DL, United Kingdom.

<u>02/2008 - 08/2008 - Support Worker.</u>

Tina Roberts, Bodmin, Cornwall, United Kingdom.

<u>05/2004 - 02/2008 - Area Supervisor/Senior Carer/Care Assistant.</u>

Care Watch Care Services LTD, Queens Way, Swansea West Industrial Park, Fforestfach, Swansea, SA5 4DH, United Kingdom.

<u>06/2002 - 05/2004 - Team Leader.</u>

Student Youths Enterprises, Swansea, United Kingdom.

<u>04-2003 - 07/2007 - Volunteer.</u>

Circus Eruption, Walter road, Swansea, United Kingdom.

01/2002 - 08/2004 - Volunteer/Working Holiday Leader.

British Trust of Conservation Volunteers, Environment centre, Pier street, Swansea, United Kingdom.

Education:

- Fullstack Software Development Diploma
- Master Practitioner of Neuro Linguistic Programming & Hypnosis Certification
- Practitioner of Neuro Linguistic Programming & Hynosis Certification.
- Open University Certificate Starting with Psychology
- Bishopston Comprehensive School, G.C.S.E's in Business Studies, English Language, English Literature, Biology, Chemistry, Physics, Electronics, Maths